Register of the Russia. Konsul'stvo (Breslau, Germany) Records, 1860-1914
Hoover Institution Archives
Russia. Konsul'stvo (Breslau, Germany) Records,
1860-1914
29005
Russia. Konsul'stvo (Breslau, Germany)
10 manuscript boxes (4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, intelligence reports, orders, and printed matter, relating to Russian-German relations, especially commercial relations
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1929.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Wroclaw (Poland); Germany; Germany--Commerce--Russia; Germany--Foreign relations--Russia; Russia; Russia--Commerce--Germany; Russia--Foreign relations--Germany; Poland
CONTAINER LIST
- General questions regarding the activity of the Foreign Office and the Service in its Department (Box 1)
  - 1884-1914
  - 1910-14
- Commission for the Reorganization of the Foreign Service, 1910-14
- General decisions and instructions of the Foreign Office concerning the Consular Service
  - 1860-1885
  - 1886-1904
  - 1905-1911
  - 1912-14
- General dispositions and instructions of the Foreign Office to the Consulate at Breslau and correspondence
  - 1906-1914
  - 1886-1904
- Correspondence regarding the personnel of the Consulate at Breslau and the rights of the Consulate, 1894-1914
- Correspondence relating to various branches of the German-Russian goods traffic (Box 2)
  - 1869-1910
  - 1911-12
  - 1913-14
- Reports of the Intelligence Office for foreign trade
  - February 1911 - Jauary 1912
  - February 1912 - June 1913
  - July 1913 - March 1914
- Selection of prices for goods on the principal Russian and foreign markets
  - 1911
  - 1912
- Reports and explanatory notes of the Consulate regarding the yearly account of the Breslau Chamber of Commerce, 1878-1896 (Box 3)
- Annual reports of the Consulate concerning its activity and yearly reviews of conditions of trade and industry in Silesia, 1895-1908
- Annual reports of the Breslau Chamber of Commerce
  - 1909
  - 1910
  - 1911
  - 1913
- Directory for Upper Silesia (Box 4)
  - Parts I-II, 1902
- Trade Register for Upper Silesia, 1902
- Administrative Handbook, 1903
- Annual reports of the Liegnitz Chamber of Commerce
  - 1910
  - 1912
  - 1913
- Annual reports of the Schweidnitz Chamber of Commerce
  - 1910
  - 1912
  - 1913
- Annual reports of the Sagan Chamber of Commerce
  - 1910
  - 1912
  - 1913
- Correspondence and reports to the Foreign Office relating to farm products and stock-farming, 1880-1914 (Box 5)
- Correspondence concerning the import of pork to Germany from Russia, 1888-1907
- Sanitary prescriptiosn in Germany prohibiting the import of cattle from Russia, 1912, 1914
- Correspondence concerning sanitary questions raised by the German authorities at the Russo-German border, 1885-1913
- Correspondence concerning the export of potatoes from Russia, 1903-1912
- Potatoe drying in Germany, 1902-1912
- Trade questions, 1884-1912
- Quarantine measures at the Russo-German border, 1889-1903
- International exhibitions, 1887-1913
- Subscription collections for charitable purposes, the erection of monuments, etc., 1886-1913
- Correspondence relating to the Russian agricultural workers in Germany
  - 1891-99
  - 1900-09 (Box 6)
- Various materials relating to Russian agricultural workers in Germany
- Private correspondence (complaints) of the Consulate with the Russian agricultural workers in Germany
  - 1911-1912
  - 1912-1913
- Russo-German commercial treaties negotiations, 1901-02
- Agreements and conventions signed by Russia with foreign powers, 1869-1913
- Reports of the Consulate to the Foreign Office and the Embassy in Berlin, 1880-1902
- Miscellaneous correspondence, 1885-1912
- Circulars and dispositions of the Foreign Office and other Departments relating to visas and passports
  - 1862-1895
  - 1896-1914 (Box 7)
- Circulars and directives of the Foreign Office respecting the passport formalities of several persons
  - 1855-1864
  - 1865-1874
  - 1875-1886
  - 1887-1914
- Register of foreign subjects debarred from admittance to Russia
  (complete register for 25 years up to 1902)
- Circulars and communications of the Police Department concerning visas, passports, and criminals (Box 8)
  - 1892-97
  - 1898-1902
  - 1903-1910
  - 1911
    - Part I
    - Part II
    - Part III (Box 9)
- His Majesty's orders, circulars, and orders of the day of the Foreign Office
  - 1863-1889
  - 1890-95
  - 1896-98
  - 1899-1901
  - 1902-04 (Box 10)
  - 1905-06
  - 1907-09
  - 1910-11
  - 1912-14
- Tariff of consular fees
- Lithographic forms for Consular correspondence on current matters